In this demo, we'll be creating a program that utilizes slices.
Once you're ready, I'll write Visual Studio Code, and let's go.
Once Visual Studio Code loads, click on the demo directory,
we're on the slices demo.
So let's scroll down here to the slices folder,
click that, and then double click on slices.go.
For this demo, we'll be creating a program that prints out a route,
like going to multiple destinations.
So we'll be using a slice to insert location to visit.
The first thing we'll do is I'm just going to make the slice right away.
So we'll create a string slice,
and we'll go to the grocery.
So we'll go to three places,
and then I'll create a function to print out this route.
So our slice will be a slice of string.
It's going to print out a new line.
And we'll have a title for the route that we're able to easily distinguish it
when we're printing it out.
And now we're going to iterate through the slice.
As long as the iterator variable is less than the length of the slice,
we'll keep going.
Remember, if you're ever working with elements of a slice or an array,
and you have the iterator variable,
you want to make a copy of it.
And that will just reduce errors later on.
That's all we have for the print slice function.
So now what we're going to do is we're going to print the slice.
We'll call this one route one, so that'll be our first route that we do.
Now we're going to modify this one.
So we have to reset it with the append, and we'll have the variable name.
And we're going to add home to the end.
This will be route two.
So our first, when we first print out the slice,
we'll get grocery department store salon.
And they're reassigning the existing route.
And we're appending home to it.
So home is going to be here on the end of the slice.
So when we print route two, it's going to have grocery department store salon home.
Next up is going to print a new line.
And we're going to visit some places.
So we'll visit route zero, and we'll just indicate that we visited it.
And we'll have the second one also be visited.
So that means at this point in the program, we've been to the grocery, and
we've been to the department store.
In order to represent this, we're going to reslise our existing slice.
So we'll reassign, and we'll go from index two to everything else.
The last thing we'll do is we'll print out our slice.
And that'll do it for the demo.
So what we're doing here is we're creating a new route with one, two, three destinations.
We're appending our home to it.
We then visit the first two destinations.
In order to represent this in the slice, we start from index two, and take the rest of the elements.
So index zero and one, those are going to be cut out.
Then we have the last ones, which are index two and three, our home here.
And then we print out the slices in each time we make a change.
And so when we run the program, we should start with three items, and
then four items, and then finally two items.
Let's run it and see what we get.
Happy to eternal, we can run this with gorun.slashdemo/slices.
And so here our first route is the grocery to partner store in the salon.
Our second route is the same as the first, but with home at the end,
we have a message indicating that we visited the grocery and
the department store, and the remaining locations are the salon and home.
This concludes the demo on working with slices.
I'll see you in the next presentation.